about to calculate the prefix sum array.
This is a common and a useful technique
in programming for cumulative
calculations. So let's proceed with this
challenge and we will move towards our VS
code. If we see in the VS code, we have
here our question along with the sample
input and output, right?So what is the
question?We have to write a JS function
to calculate the prefix sum array of
a given array, right?And here we have the
input and we have the output as well. OK,
first of all, what we are going to do, we
will come down and we will break down our
question. OK, so I will write here what
JS function. OK, after that, what is the
next important thing in this question?
That we have to calculate the prefix
sum array of a given array, right?So we
will take this line and we will put it
over here. OK, now let us come at line
#7 and we will define our function name.
So what will be our function name?We will
keep our function name as what prefix
sum. OK, that is what we want to
calculate. So we will keep our function
name as what prefix sum with a
parenthesis, OK. Now let us
understand this particular line how we
are going to calculate the prefix sum
array of a given array. OK, so
for that we will go to our input and
output. OK, so I will take this input
array down. OK and now let us understand
from this input array how can we reach to
this particular output. OK, so let us
take this here and I will put it over
here. So first one is our input array and
second one is our what output array. OK,
now if you come here, what is?Here 2.
So that is nothing but the first element
of our input array, correct?So I will
just write here 2. OK, after that what do
you have?You have 6. Now how can you
reach to six?If you see here 2 +
4, right?It is saying sum. So let us
do the sum here. So prefix sum. OK,
prefix means what before, correct?So
that is what we have to do here. So
4 2, if you take, you will get here
6, right?So that is what we are going to
do. So I will write here 2 + 4 is nothing
but six. OK. After that, what do we have?
10. So as soon as you go to the next
element, and if you start adding it, 2 +
4 + 4, it will be nothing but what?
10, right?So I'll write here what?2 + 4 +
4. This is what?8 + 2 is nothing but 10,
right?That is what we are going to get.
After that, what we have?We have 12. So
how will you get it?Add this.
2+4+4+2. So I will write
here what?
2+4+4+2. So
what you will get?You will get 12. So
that is what it is doing. It is adding
the prefix sum. So 2 first time.
After that 2+4, that is where you are
getting 6. After that 2+4+4,
that is giving you 10, and after that
2+4+4+2, and it isgiving you
12. That is how you are reaching to an
output array like this. Now we understood
that how we can reach to this particular
output, right?So for this now we are
going to write our approach. OK, so I
will write here approach. So what is a
prefix sum array?It is nothing but the
array whose every element is the sum of
all the elements of the original array up
to the current index. OK, so if you see
what we were doing, first we took here 2
and that was our output. After thatWhat
we did to get our six, we added here 2 +
4, right?To get 10 what we added then 2 +
4 + 4, right?So if you see we are
traveling from one element to another,
right?And we are maintaining our running
sum here, right?That is what we have
done. So we will come down and for this
question we are going to use a loop
because we are traveling from one element
to another element, right?So I will write
here loop and we are going to take just
one loop. So I will write here what I
loop, OK. Now, after that, whenever we
use a loop, what we have here, we have
our start point and our end point, right?
So where it is going to start, obviously,
it is going to start at our 0th index,
right?So I will write here what?Start
will be our zero, right?But where it is
going to end?It will end at
arr.length-1 because we have to reach to
our last element, right?So I will write
here what?arr.length-1, correct?
Now let us come here and we will write
loop here. So I will write here what for
and then it will be what let i is equal
to 0 and i should be less than
our arr.length, correct?And then we are
going to increment as well, okay?And then
here we are going to write our flower
braces. Now inside this flower braces
what we have to do, we have to calculate
the sum, correct?And then after
calculating the sum it is going to
accumulate somewhere, right?You can see
here accumulation is happening. So we
have toto calculate the sum and we have
to accumulate plus what we have to
do here, we have to push it to our
resultant array, right?So we are going to
write here what push to resultant array,
correct?So that is what I will write
here. We have to calculate the sum
and we have to accumulate the sum,
correct?And then we have to push to our
resultant array, correct?So now for
thisWhat we will do, we will come at the
top and we will declare here 2 variables.
OK, so first variable will be what some
prefix. OK, so I will write here some
prefix and we are going to initialize
with an empty array. Why I'm doing this?
Because this is the place where we will
store our prefix sum. OK, so this will be
used to store the prefix. So I will
write here what store the prefix sum. OK,
after that what we are going to do, we
will declare another variable called as a
sum and we will initialize with zero. OK,
so here this place what it is going to
happen. We are going to calculate the sum
and here we will be accumulating it up.
OK, so I will write here accumulation is
going to happen here. OK. Now let us come
here and we will write the logic for
that. So what we are going to write to
calculate the sum and to do the
accumulation, we will write here what sum
plus is equal to our arr of I,
right. That is what is going to give us
our sum. And after that what we will do,
we will use our push method in this. OK,
so push method will what do it will add
up the elements to our empty array. OK,
So what element we want to add, we want
to add our sum, right. So we will come
here. And we will write here what sum
prefix we are going to write so and
dot push we will write and here we are
going to pass our sum. OK, once
everything is done we are going to print
our what?Final resultant array.
That is nothing but our sum prefix, right?
That is where we are going to get our
exact output. OK, now let us come here
and we will understand our iteration. OK,
so I will write here what iterations. OK
now when I is equal to 0, what we are
going to write our condition 0 is less
than 4. Why 4?Because the length of the
array is 4, right?Then what will happen
once this condition turns out to be true,
it is going to perform this operations.
So is it true?Yes, it is true. So it is
going to perform the operation, right?
What is the operation?Sum plus is equal
to arr of I. So what is this?This is
nothing but sum is equal to sum plus
arr of I, right?That is what we are going
to write here. And let us come here and
let us do that. That is what zero we will
get here plus what is our arr of I?That
is nothing but two. So you will get here
as two. And this is what our sum. So
sum is equal to two. After this, what is
written?In the next slide we have to use
our push method and we have to update our
resultant array, right?So I will write
here our push method and we are going to
push what two. So our resultant array
that is nothing but some prefix will have
inside too. OK, now next
iteration is going to happen. So I will
write here what I is equal to 1 and one
less than four we are going to write here
and this is also true, right?So that is
why now for the calculations will happen.
So what is it?So sum plus arr of I. Now
sum value has got updated. It is what it
is nothing but two right?And two plus our
arr of I. So we have your what 4 right?
So 2 + 4 we are going to write and that
is what we are going to get 6 and our sum
will be nothing but six. So after this we
are going to use our push method right?So
I will write here what push. And then we
are going to push it to our resultant
array. So we already had two and then we
are going to push our six also inside it.
So if you see we got our two comma six.
OK, now let us go to the next iteration.
So when I is equal to two, so we are
going to write here what 2 is less than
four and this is also true, right?That is
where now calculations will happen. So
our sum value was updated as six. So we
will write here 6. And what is our next
element?That is nothing but four, right?
So I will write here four, that is
nothing but 10. So our sum will hold
what our 10, right?And that is where we
are going to get here sum is equal to 10
and we will then push this out, right?So
I'm going to. Here our push method and in
this array it is going to have now 2
comma 6 comma 10. OK that is what
we are going to get here. OK now in the
next iteration what will happen now?So
let us come here and we are going to
write here what I is equal to three. OK
so three is less than four. Now this is
also true right?So we will come here and
we will write here T OK for true I am
writing after that what is our sum value
now it is nothing but 10 because it's
updated right?So 10 plus we are
going to write now what is our last
element here that is 2. So I will write
here what two and this is nothing but 12
and what will be our sum value now. So
sum will become your nothing but as what
12 right?And then finally we are going
to push it inside our resultant element.
So we will have here what 2 comma 6
comma 10 comma 12 right?So I
will write here 10 comma 12. This will be
our final resultant area. OK and that
is what you are going to get it that as
well. So this is what we will be
achieving it after that. OK now
after that what will happen?When I
is equal to four. OK now we will test
our condition because I have told you N
number of times we are writing plus plus
it is going to increment it. But when it
tests the condition that time it
terminates. OK so if you write your 4 is
less than four right?And here you get
your false right?And this is the place
where your condition is going to fail.
And the loop is going to terminate. OK,
so final termination will happen and you
will have in your resultant array this
one and that is where after this we are
going to print our resultant array. That
is what I will take it here and we are
going to put it over here. So finally
then we will print our sum prefix. OK,
now let us come down and we will
implement the same approach inside our
function also. OK, so I will write here
what function and what will be our
function name. Nothing but prefix sum
and we will quickly invoke it. OK, so I
will write here what prefix sum and I am
going to pass our input array. So let us
take it from above. So this is our input
array and we will pass it over here. OK
and let us receive it here as in params.
So I will write here what arr OK and let
us just console it out. So I will write
here what console dot log of arr
OK and. Let us come here and we
will write here what node 72 challenge,
right?And we will hit enter. What do we
got?2 comma 4 comma 4 comma 2. That is
nothing but our input array, right?So
this function is properly running. OK,
now let us come above and we will see our
approach and accordingly we are going to
do. So we are going to now create our two
variables. OK, so I will write here what
let sumprefix is equal to and we are
going to initialize this with an empty
array, correct?And then we willHere and
we will write here what let sum is equal
to 0 correct?After that we are going
to write our I loop. OK, so we will
come here and we will write here what for
and then let I is equal to 0 correct
and where it should end.
arr.length-1 that is where we are going
to write here what arr.length
okay and then i++ we are going to
write and in this I will show you by
printing our i okay so I will write here
what console.log of i okay now let us
come here and I will write here what node
day 72 challenge and we will hit enter
what do you got 0 1 2 and 3 if you see we
have written the same at i is equal to 4
the loop is getting terminated so only
this many iterations are going to happen.
OK. That is what we have seen here. OK.
Now I will just comment this out and we
will come down and we will now start
calculating our sum and accumulating it
in our sum variable and after that we are
going to push it as well. OK. So let us
write here what sum plus is equal to
arr of i. OK. And after that what we are
going to do sumprefix.
Push our sum. OK, I have written here
and I will show you now what is the sum
here. I will come here and I'll write
here what console dot logsum. OK
and let us write here our I also OK
so that we can see here what we are
getting. OK so I'll write here I comma
sum. So we will come here and we will
clear it up and I will write here what
node 72 challenge and we will hit
enter. So if you see at 0 the sum
is what two right?That is what we have
done. When it is one it is. Nothing but
six. So that is where it is getting
pushed 6 also. Then we have here 10, so
you can see here 10. Then we have here
12, right?And we are getting here 12. OK,
so that is what we are able to get it. So
after each iteration we are printing our
sum right now in the terminal. OK, now
let us come here and we have already
pushed this. So we will come outside our
loop and we are going to console our sum
prefix. OK, so I will write here what sum
prefix and we can just see in the
terminal now. So let us clear it up and I
will write here what node day 72
challenge and we will hit enter. What do
we got 2610 and 12. So same thing
we have pushed it inside our resultant
array that is nothing but our sum prefix
and we are getting here the final output.
OK now let us come here and we will
improvise it. So sum prefix of a
given array we will take up and we will
pass it here inside our template
literals, right?So let us come here and I
will write here this template. literals
and we will paste it here and we will put
here comma okay and given array we will
remove and I will write here what square
bracket flower braces right
and then we will write here what our arr
Correct. And now we will make this P also
capital. OK, now let us come here and we
will just test it out, clear it up. Note
day 72 challenge and we will hit enter.
What do you got?See prefix of an array is
this right?That is what is our output 2
comma 6 comma 10 comma 12. OK now
let us remove this console dot log
statements OK which we used it for
debugging purpose or commenting this
console dot log commenting this console
dot log right. And now let us come here
and we will write here what clear it up
node day 72 challenge and we will hit
enter. You can see here prefix sum array
of a. 2 comma 4 comma
4 comma 2 is what 2, 6, 10 and 12. We
can write here and also of an array is
this. OK, now let us come here and we can
just invoke it with another input. So I
will just write here what 10 comma 20
comma 30. OK, so I'll write here prefix
sum and we will write here what 10 comma
20 comma 30. Now what will be the output?
10 comma 30 we will get and after that
what we are going to get 60, right?Let us
clear it up and see. Note 72
challenge. Hit enter. See 1030 and
60 right?You can test it out with
different inputs. OK, you will get the
exact output OK. Now let us
come here and we will have a quick recap
of this particular question. OK, So what
we have to do, we have to write a GS
function to calculate the prefix sum
array of a given array, right?And here we
had our sample input and output, right?We
understood that we have to write a GS
function. That is where we defined our
function name as what prefix sum, right?
And at line #8 we wrote the important
chunk of this question, that is what we
have to calculate the prefix sum array of
a given number. We understood here from
line #10 to 14 that how we can
reach to our particular output, right?And
that is where for that we wrote our
approach also, right?So what is a prefix
array?It is nothing but the array whose
every element is the sum of all the
elements of the original array up to the
current index, right?So we are traveling
from one index to another index, right?
That is where we are going to use your
loop, OK, and we used our I loop, correct?
What was?the start point?It was 0, and
what was the end?Nothing but
arr.length -1, right?And then we
came here and we wrote our loop, right?
Now inside the loop what we had to do, we
had to calculate the sum, then we have to
accumulate, and then finally we have to
push to our resultant array, right?That
is where we defined here another two
variables, right?That is nothing but sum
prefix and we initialized with an empty
array. Then we again declared here what's
sum and we initialized with 0. Right
then we came down and we wrote our
operations right to calculate the sum and
to push it to our resultant array by
using a push method right?And then down
we understood our iterations right?
After the iterations are completed we are
going to print it here our sum prefix
right?And we also understood in the
iteration that when I is equal to 4A loop
is going to terminate because the
condition fails. Hence that is the end
of the loop and finally we will get our
sum prefix. That is nothing but our
resultant array, right?Then the same
thing we wrote inside our function also
and we defined here function as what?
Prefix sum and we were receiving here as
an arr, right?And then we just tested
out our function by writing
console.log that we were
passing it from here and we are receiving
it here or not, right?Then we declared
here our two variables, that is sum
prefix is equal to empty array, sum is
equal to zero. Then we wrote our i loop
andAnd then we did our calculations
that is for the addition and then we used
a push method to push it to our resultant
array, right?Then at line number 49, we
came here and we printed our sum prefix
also and we improvised our
console.log statement also, right?And at
line number 51 and 52, we invoked it with
different inputs, right?And we tested in
the terminal, okay?You can invoke it one
more time and I will just write here what
prefix sum and we will pass here one
Comma one comma one. OK, let us see what
do we get. OK, so we will come here and
we will clear it up and we will write
here what node day 72 challenge and we
will hit enter. If you see we are getting
here what?One, two, three, four, right?
That is nothing but if you add it, it is
going to give you one, two and three and
four. That is what is our resultant area,
right?Now I will tell you guys why this
challenge is useful. This prefix sum
technique is widely used in various
computational problems, including range
queries, cumulative calculations and
dynamic programming. This challenge helps
us to understand the logic and the
practice of the implementation of
cumulative sums efficiently. OK.